现在是听力试音时间。
Guess what? I'm going to Chiang Mai in two weeks.
Wow, sounds like fun.
But I believe that April is the hottest month of the year there.
Yes, that's true.
But there is a water festival there from April the 13th to the 15th.
I wonder if it's similar to the water festival of the Dai people in Yunnan province.
Yes, I think so.
This is the time of the Thai New Year.
People go on the streets to throw water at each other.
Cool. But why do they do that?
Because the New Year is the time for cleaning and washing away bad things.
Then you have good luck in the New Year.
试音到此结束。
The hearing over.
听力考试正式开始。
第一部分：听力。
一、听句子，根据所听到的内容选择正确答语
每小题念两遍。
听完每句话后，你都有五秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
Could you please pass me the
Could you please pass me the dictionary?
二，听句子，选择与所听句子内容相符的图片
Choose time. I got back my watch at last and found.
每小题念两遍。
听前，你将有五秒钟的读图时间；
听完后，每小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
My little sister has long straight hair.
little sister answer
三，听对话，根据对话内容及问题选择正确答案。
每小题念两遍。
听完每段对话后。
哦，你都有五秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
11. Excuse me, is there a cinema in this shopping center?
No, there isn't, but you can find one between the hotel and the bank on Lanshan
Street. Question, where does the woman want to go?
Excuse me, is there a cinema in this shopping center?
No, there isn't, but you can find one between the hotel and the bank on Lanshan
Street. Question, where does the woman want to go?
12. Look at the dark clouds, it's going to rain.
Yeah, but the radio says it will be fine tomorrow.
Question, how's the weather now?
at the dark clouds, it's going to rain.
Yeah, but the radio says it will be fine tomorrow.
Question, how's the weather now?
13. What do you want to be when you grow up?
I'd like to be an actress.
I've heard you dream of being an engineer, right?
No, I want to be a reporter.
Question, what does the boy want to be?
What do you want to be when you grow up?
I'd like to be an actress.
I've heard you dream of being an engineer, right?
No, I want to be a reporter.
Question, what does the boy want to be?
14. The blue dress looks nice, how much is it?
200 yuan. Can I try it on?
Sure. Question, where are probably the two speakers?
Number 15. Hello, is Alan there?
Sorry, it's Dale.
He's reading in the library.
Could I take a message for him?
Yes, this is Sandy.
Could you please tell him to call me back?
There are some changes for our school trip.
Question, what's Alan doing now?
Hello, is Alan there?
Sorry, it's Dale.
He's reading in the library.
Could I take a message for him?
Yes, this is Sandy.
Could you please tell him to call me back?
There are some changes for our school trip.
Question, what's Alan doing now?
Number 16. My bike is broken.
Could you help me to fix it up, Tony?
Sorry, can't, Mary.
You'd better ask Andy for help.
Question, whose bike is broken?
Number 17. Emily, you usually go to school by car?
No, I usually go to school by bus.
But my father gave me a this morning because it was raining.
Question, how did the girl go to school this morning?
Emily, do you usually go to school by car?
No, I usually go to school by bus.
But my father gave me a this morning because it was raining.
Question, how did the girl go to school this morning?
Number 18. You were absent from classes this morning.
What happened? I didn't feel well, Mr.
I had a sore throat and sore doctor.
Question, what's the probable relationship between the two speakers?
You were absent from classes this morning.
What happened? I didn't feel well, Mr.
I had a sore throat and sore doctor.
Question, what's the probable relationship between the two speakers?
Number 19. Hey, Maria,
what club did you join at school?
The drama club, of course.
How about you?
The music club.
I like playing the violin.
Question, what's are they talking about?
Hey, Maria, what club did you join at school?
The drama club, of course.
How about you?
The music club.
I like playing the violin.
Question, what's are they talking about?
Number 20. Can I see your ticket, please?
Yes, here you are.
This ticket is for Oxford.
Yes, that's right.
But this train doesn't go to Oxford.
It goes to What?
Liverpool? Oh, no.
Question, what happened to the man?
Can I see your ticket, please?
Yes, here you are.
This ticket is for Oxford.
Yes, that's right.
But this train doesn't go to Oxford.
It goes to Liverpool.
What? Liverpool? Oh, no.
Question, what happened to the man?
四，听短文，根据短文内容选择正确答案。
短文念两遍。
听前，你将有十五秒钟的读题时间。
听完后，每小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
Question, man? Question, to man?
Question, Question, happened to
Question, man? Question, happened the man?
Question, Question, what happened
Question, happened the man?
man? Question, what happened to the man?
Question, what to the man?
Question, to to Question,
happened to the man?
Question, what happened to the the man?
Question, to Question, to
Question, happened to Question, to
Question, what happened to the man?
Question, Question, to In the evening, we are going to the teahouse to drink tea and
enjoy the face changing performance.
Call me if necessary.
Hope you have fun today.
Any questions? Question, to
五，听短文，根据短文内容完成图表中所缺信息。
短文念三遍。
听前，你将有二十五秒钟的读题时间。
Question, happened what happened man?
what happened to the man?
Question, what Question, what happened to the man?
Question, what happened
Question, man? Question, to
Question, what man?
Question, what happened man?
man? Question, what happened to the man?
Question, to to How to celebrate the day?
stay with your family.
Have a big dinner together, help around the house, or simply chat with them.
Besides, reflect on what family means to you.
Your parents give birth to you, bring you up, and are always there for you.
Express thanks to your family.
this is also a good chance to build a good relationship with other families.
Great people in your community, or give a hand to families who need help.
It can bring you closer.
Dear classmates, have you heard of the International Day of the Families?
It's on May the 15th every year.
Who made it, and why?
Well, in 1993, the UN, that is, the United Nations, started it to help us understand
how important families are.
It is our families that make up the world we are living in.
The day also reminds us that not all families are living happily.
Some are broken, some are poor and hungry.
So we need to make efforts to help these families for a better world.
How to celebrate the day?
First, stay with your family.
Have a big dinner together.
Help around the house or simply chat with them.
Besides, reflect on what family means to you.
Your parents give birth to you, bring you up, and are always there for you.
Express thanks to your family.
Last, this is also a good chance to build a good relationship with other families.
Greet people in your community or give a hand to families who need help.
It can bring you closer.
Dear classmates, have you heard of the International Day of Families?
It's on May the 15th every year.
Who made it, and why?
Well, in 1993, the UN, that is, the United Nations, started it to help us understand
how important families are.
It is our families that make up the world we are living in.
The day also reminds us that not all families are living happily.
Some are broken, some are poor and hungry.
So, we need to make efforts to help these families for a better world.
How to celebrate the day?
First, stay with your family.
Have a big dinner together.
Help around the or simply chat with them.
Besides, reflect on what family means to you.
Your parents give birth to you, bring you up, and are always there for you.
Express thanks to your family.
Last, this is also a good chance to build a good relationship with other families.
people in your community or give a hand to families who need help.
It can bring you closer.
听力录音到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间将。答案转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you for watching.
Thank